

Profile

I am an experienced DevOps Engineer and System Administrator that specializes in DevOps engineering, Linux administration, and team leadership. I use creative infrastructure design to improve performance, reduce downtime, and lower expenses. I thrive in troubleshooting, team building, and efficient communication in AWS, Linux, Jenkins, Prometheous, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Shell scripting, and Github.

Employment History

DevOps Engineer at Incaendo Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Noida

February 2024 — Present

- Managing AWS infrastructure, including writing Infrastructure as Code (IAC) for AWS services and MongoDB configurations.
- Developing Shell scripts for both code and infrastructure automation purposes.
- Collaborating with development and operations teams to streamline processes and improve overall efficiency.
- Implementing security best practices throughout the development and deployment lifecycle.
- Optimizing system performance and ensuring high availability of applications and services.
- Automated server provisioning and configuration management, resulting in faster deployment and easier maintenance
- Developed a Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipeline that improved system reliability and uptime
- Implemented security measures to protect against malicious attacks and ensure data privacy
- Created dashboards to visually represent system performance metrics
- Implemented a logging and monitoring solution that enabled early detection and resolution of system issues
- Developed scripts to automate manual tasks, resulting in improved system efficiency and cost savings

DevOps Engineer at Zenberry Digitals Private Limited, BengaluruAugust 2020 — January 2024

- Developed a Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipeline that improved system reliability and uptime
- Automated server provisioning and configuration management, resulting in faster deployment and easier maintenance
- Setting up an AWS EC2 instance.
- Setup and manage mail servers using Postfix, Dovecot, and Roundcube.
- Set up and configure a Linux RDP server on AZURE.

Details

India

+91 74798 43211

anurag.sharma.kush@gmail.com

Links

linkedin

Skills

Linux

Python

Amazon Web Services

Terraform

CicleCI

Docker

Nginx & Apache

Ubuntu (Operating System)

Scripting

Cloudflare

Github

HA proxy load balancer

DNS Management

Amazon RDS

RDBMS

kubernetes

Amazon MSK

Prometheus

Languages

English

Hindi

- Configure Nginx and Apache servers (including nginx server blocks for many domains) to meet project and client requirements.
- Experience with AWS Network Firewall and Linux Firewall.
- Amazon ECS, Lightsail, AWS shield, AWS cloudtrail & cloudwatch.
- Setting up microservices on single nginx server on multiple port.
- Working with Terraform for cloud infrastructure Automation.
- · Working with Zabbix for monitoring.
- · Worked with Jenkins and shell script

AWS & Server Administrator at Kalash Enterprises, Bhopal

August 2018 — July 2020

- Key role is to maintain webserver, websites & mail server.
- DNS Management.
- Website Development And Deployement (Wordpress, Opencart etc.).
- Control Panel Management.
- I worked as a React JS developer on different projects, including Ecommerce.
- Setting up C-panel, WHM, Plesk, and Virtualmin on a Linux server.
- Worked with cross-functional design teams to create software solutions that improved overall functionality and performance.
- Collaborated with team to determine application requirement specifications.
- Installed, configured, and maintained enterprise-level Linux and Windows server systems
- Automated server provisioning and configuration management, resulting in faster deployment and easier maintenance
- Implemented a REST API integration that dynamically retrieved and synchronized data from the server to the mobile application

Education

Bachelor of Technology, Kalinga University, Raipur

June 2014 — July 2018

Intermediate, Bihar School Examination Board, Patna

May 2010 — April 2012

Matriculation, Central Board of Secondary Education, Patna

March 2008 — April 2009

★ Additional Skills

Amazon Services

 AWS EC2 	AWS CLOUDWATCH	AWS ACM
 AWS IAM 	AWS ECR	AWS KMS
 AWS VPC 	AWS ECS	ROUTE 53
 AWS S3 	AWS SES	AWS LOAD
BALANCER		

HA proxy load balancer

Zabbix

Project Planning

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above particulars of facts and information stated are correct to the best of my belief and knowledge.

ANURAG KUMAR